Miguel Vicente Ortega Santiago

Web Developer

Penrith, NSW Australia | M: 0499 398 311 | E: santiagomiguelvicente@gmail.com | L: www.linkedin.com/in/miguel-vicente-ortega-santiago

React Developer Portfolio: https://miguelvicentesantiago.vercel.app/ Angular Developer Portfolio: https://santiagomiguelvicente.vercel.app/

TECH SKILLS

- C#, .NET Framework, LINQ, Entity Framework
- MvSQL
- MongoDb
- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap
- NPM
- React
- MS Office
- · GIT/Github
- PHP
- Laravel
- Vue
- Webpack
- Babel
- SASS/LESS
- LANSA
- RPG/400
- COBOL

TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS

- Time Management
- Adaptability
- Teamwork
- Analytical skills
- · Problem-solving skills
- Innovative
- Troubleshooting skills
- Proactive

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

MongoDB University

- M001: MongoDB Basics May 2018
- M101JS: MongoDB for NodeJS Developers September 2018

LANSA

Lansa Integrator Course March 2012

Computer Power

Graduate Certificate in Object
 Oriented Programming August 2005

LinkedIn

- PHP with MySQL Essential Training: 1
 The Basics November 2018
- PHP with MySQL Essential Training: 2 Build a CMS November 2018
- PHP Essential Training November 2018
- Learning PHP October 2018

EDUCATION

University of the East - Caloocan city, PH

ABOUT ME

Experienced Analyst/Programmer with over a decade of experience. I am currently on an internship at MVPStudio where in just a month, I have gained much practical experience in Full Stack Web Development. Developed an ASP.NET Core MVC app with React, and database on Microsoft SQL Server. I deployed the Web App and database on Azure - https://mvpstore.azurewebsites.net I am assigned on the Talent project and for the second sprint I implemented enhancements to the Employer Profile page. And I implemented the Manage Jobs page to display the jobs posted by Employer as a list of Cards. I also implemented the edit and close functions on the Job Summary card.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern

MVP Studio

June 2021 - Present

- C#, ASP.NET Core MVC, HTML/JavaScript/AJAX/CSS/jQuery, MS SQL
- Developed an ASP.NET Core MVC app with React. Created the database on Microsoft SQL Server. https://mvpstore.azurewebsites.net/
- Done revisions on the Talent project:
 - Added Last Name to the Primary Contact Details of the Employer Profile and implemented the Edit button on the Company Contact Details.
 - 2. Implemented the Manage Jobs page.

http://mvptalentmazurewebsites.net/

Web Development Volunteer Contributor

Charistay

April 2021 - April 2021

• I solved their issue of the mailchimp popup appearing immediately instead of the 30-second delay that they want.

Junior Web Development Bootcamp Graduate

Generation Australia in Partnership with Academy Xi

Nov 2020 - Mar 2021

- Completed the full-time intensive web development program by Generation Australia and facilitated by AcademyXi
- Skills and Languages covered: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, NPM as well as behavioural/people skills to support job readiness
- Completed a final project (development of Task-Planner Web App) using the skills learned across the course

Analyst/Programmer

PRUDENTIAL INVESTMENT COMPANY OF AUSTRALIA

Feb 2008 - Dec 2018

- Maintained and added modules to the Portfolio Management System which is running on the AS/400 and developed using LANSA
 - In example, I added the Online Invoice Approval module that sped up the processing of thousands of invoices per day
- Done maintenance changes on the company's intranet site which is developed in Java EE and run under the IBM Portal platform
- Created new and revised existing Crystal Report definitions and the stored procedure written in LANSA to get data from PMS

Java Programmer Trainee

IC CONSULTING

Jun 2005 - Jan 2008

• Studied Java programming and got certified as Sun Cerified Java Programmer

 Bachelor of Business Administration, Majoring in Accounting, 1990

REFERENCES

- Robin Klaus Instructor at Generation Australia JWD program
- Anthony Belz Senior Analyst/Programmer at PICA
- Natalie Wedd Systems Development Manager at PICA

OTHER LANGUAGES

PILIPINO/TAGALOG

- Compose Change request proposals based on requirements of the client
- Develop/revise Java Server Pagess, Java servlets and Enterprise Java Beans for the change requests from clients

Analyst/Programmer

Software Laboratories Incorporated Oct 2000 - Dec 2002

Assigned at GOODYEAR PHILIPPINES

 Develop/revise RPG/400 programs as per specifications approved by the users for additional reports on the AS/400 systems

Analyst/Programmer

MASTECH ASIA PACIFIC, Sydney Australia Sep 1998 - Aug 2000 Assigned at ASTRE Automotive Group

- Develop/revise RPG/400 or RPG IV programs as per specifications prepared by the JBA Business Analyst
- Investigated issues and explained whether it was a system setup issue, data conversion or if something was wrong with the program

Assigned at SSA ASIA PACIFIC

- Make high level estimates on what are the required activities and corresponding man-hours to satisfy
 user requirements
- · Make technical design according to user requirements
- · Develop/revise AS/SET definition according to technical design

Analyst/Programmer

EASTERN TELECOMS PHILS. INC.

May 1997 - Sep 1998

- One of the Developers that developed and implemented the Customer Service Systsem using RPG and CL/400
- · Maintained and provided user support for the Billing system

EDP Manager

AMOY FASHION GLOVES, XIAMEN CHINA

May 1994 - Mar 1997

- Studied the manufacturing system developed in New York and implemented the system in the Factory
- Provide user training for the system

Analyst/Programmer

Software Laboratories Incorporated Oct 2000 - Dec 2002

Assigned at SMITHKLINE BEECHAM PHILIPPINES

· Design and implement additional reports on the JD Edwards accounting package

Programmer

RUSTAN'S COMMERCIAL CORPORATION

Feb 1990 - Jul 1993

- COBOL programming on the different systems running on the NCR 9050 mainframe.
- Saved the Comapny Time and Money by Developing and implementing the MTS Preparation system on the PC using FoxBASE+ and developing the interface programs on the AS/400